EL IBAOUI OTMANE



.NET/.NET CORE/C#
MICROSOFT AZURE CLOUD/
INGENIEUR CONCEPTEUR
DEVELOPPEUR SENIOR

Contact:



otmelib@gmail.com



(+33) 06 59 05 85 12



Paris, France



https://www.linkedin.com/in/otmane-el-ibaoui/

ABOUT ME:

Computer engineer specialized in Microsoft technologies, expert in web development and APIs with .NET and .NET Core. Skilled in deploying Azure cloud solutions, designing relational databases, and utilizing Azure DevOps. Committed to using agile methodologies to enhance delivery efficiency.

Professional Experience:

Allianz AGI

(Juillet 2024- Aujourd'hui)

DEVELOPER FULL-STACK Achievements:

Responsible for developing a business evaluation application to determine companies' eligibility for Allianz investments. Contributed to formalizing functional requirements and translating them into technical specifications. Developed the front-end using Angular 15 (TypeScript, RxJS, SCSS) and the back-end with .NET 8, following a Clean Architecture approach and utilizing SQL Server. Acted as the technical lead for the back-end and managed CI/CD pipelines using GitHub Actions to automate deployments. Collaborated closely with the front-end team and leveraged tools like Swagger and Postman to ensure quality and delivery efficiency.

Technologies:

- .Net 8, .Net Core, Angular 15, Microservice Architecture, Asp.Net WebApi, SQL Server
- Microsoft Azure (Web Apps, Azure Functions, Azure Blob Storage, Azure SQL Database, Azure Data factory)
- Hangfire, Entity Framwork, C#, NUnit, SpecFlow, Visual Studio 2022, GitHub, CI/CD AutoMapper, FluentValidators, Git, ...

SNCF SQUIREL:

(Mars 2021- juin 2024)

.NET /.NET CORE / C# LEAD BACKEND DEVELOPER

Projects

- OuiGo (OuiNews, LEO, App Client, Canaries, OuiFi)
- JuniorCie(AppClient, Portail Agent, Information Voyageur)

Achievements:

As a Senior Developer and Lead Developer, I contributed to the development of APIs consumed by our front-end applications, from design to production deployment. I supervised junior developers, introduced high-quality coding practices, and conducted code reviews to maintain standards. Leveraging various Azure services, I established robust application architectures, configured CI/CD pipelines, and developed unit tests. Additionally, I designed relational databases and transformed functional requirements into detailed technical specifications, ensuring optimal and secure solutions.

Méthodologie : Agile SCRUM

Technologies:

- .Net 5/6, .Net Core, Microservice Architecture, Asp.Net WebApi, SQL Server
- Microsoft Azure (Web Apps, Azure Functions, Azure Blob Storage, Azure SQL Database, Application Insight)
- Hangfire, Entity Framwork, C#, NUnit, SpecFlow, Visual Studio 2022, Azure DevOps (Azure DevOps for CI/CD pipelines), AutoMapper, FluentValidators, Git, ...

GROUPE AFNOR:

(Juillet 2019 - Déc 2020)

.NET CORE / C# SENIOR Fullstack DEVELOPER Achievements:

As an experienced developer, I contributed to:

The complete redesign of the Standards Store: developed a new online store for Afnor Edition to facilitate the sale of standards, as well as the creation of its back office.

The development of a back-office system for order tracking and configuration of the Standards Store.

Education:

ECOLE MAROCAINE DES SCIENCES DE L'INGENIEUR (EMSI) MIAGE

2016

DISTINCTIONS

MICROSOFT IMAGINE CUP Vice-champion 2016

Langues:

Français	
Anglais	
Arabe	

Technologies:

Visual Studio 2019, Git, Azure Devops, PostgreSql, C# 7, Asp.Net Core 2.2.0, Asp MVC Core, Architecture, Asp.Net WebApi, Entity Framework Core, WebApi 2, RestSharp, Owin, Log4Net, AutoMapper, Fluent Validator, NUnit, SpecFlow, Bootstrap, JavaScript, Jquery,...

XPOLLENS (NATIXIS):

(Février 2018 – Mai 2019)

.NET CORE / C# Fullstack DEVELOPER

Achievements:

As a junior developer, I participated in:

The analysis, estimation, design, development, testing, and securing of APIs used by our partners (Marketplaces) to manage online payments and ensure seamless interactions between marketplaces, their clients, vendors, and banks.

The analysis, estimation, design, and development of dedicated back-office systems for each partner.

The creation of a registration process for BPCE as part of their online banking project.

Technologies:

Visual Studio 2015, Git, TFS, SqlServer 2012, C# 7, Asp.Net 4.6.2, Asp MVC 5, Architecture, Asp.Net, WebApi, Razor, HTML 5, Entity Framework 6, Nhibernate, WebApi 2, Log4Net, AutoMapper, Fluent Validator, Windows Services, NUnit, Angular 5, TypeScript, Bootstrap, JavaScript, Jquery,...

CDISCOUNT:

(Mars 2016 – Janvier 2018)

.NET CORE / C# JUNIOR Fullstack DEVELOPER

Projects: Cdiscount, Cdiscount PRO, SellerZone, and GoSpor

Achievements:

As a junior developer, I contributed to:

The analysis, estimation, design, development, testing, maintenance, and evolution of the applications.

Writing and optimizing SQL queries for data retrieval.

Debugging and fixing issues under the supervision of senior developers.

Assisting in code reviews and participating in daily stand-up meetings to ensure alignment with team objectives.

Collaborating with the QA team to reproduce and resolve bugs.

Technologies:

Visual Studio 2015, TFS, Sql Server 2016, C# 6, Asp.Net MVC 5, Razor, HTML 5, SQL, WebApi 2, NUnit, Sonar, FxCop, StyleCop, jira

Compétences:

<u>Framework et langages</u>: C#, SQL, JS, HTML, CSS ASP.NET 5, 6 et +, ASP.Net Core, Entity Framework, .Net 5+, .Net Core

<u>Méthodologie</u>: SCRUM, OOP, Principes SOLID, Clean Architectures

<u>Cloud Microsoft Azure</u>: Azure App Service, Azure Functions, Azure SQL Database, Azure Storage, Azure Service Bus, Azure DevOps

Databases: SQL Server, PostgreSQL, MySQl, SqLite

<u>Outils</u>: Visual studio, Git, Postman, Teams, Microsoft SqlServer Management Studio, Jira, Azure Devops, GitHub

<u>Soft Skills</u>: Communication, Travail en équipe et collaboration, Résolution de problèmes, Adaptabilité et apprentissage continu, Créativité et innovation, Esprit critique et prise de décision